A Finding Aid to the Ruth Bowman Papers, 1936-2006, bulk 1963-1999, in the Archives of American Art AAA.bowmruth2
Archives of American Art
- Interviews, 1963-1989; Series 5; 9.2 Linear feet Boxes 12-25
  - KUSC "Sounds of Seeing", 1979-1983 (Box 14)
    - Mary Alexander; Willow Young; Tressa Miller; Lynn Kienholz, 1982 June 30-1982 September 9; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Patrick Houlihan, Southwest Museum; Merle Shipper; Richard Koshalek, Museum of Contemporary Art Los Angeles; Patrick Ela, Craft and Folk Art Museum; Liz King, 1982 September 15-1982 October; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Mary Jane Hewitt; Regina Perry, 1982 December 15-1982 December 20; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Barbara Goldstein; Bob Smith, Los Angeles Institute of Contemporary Art; Michael Newton, 1982 December 22-1983 January 5; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Louise Nevelson, 1983 April 6; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Charlotte Rubinstein; Claire Isaacs; Maudette Ball, 1983 May 4-1983 July 20; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Nancy Berman; Juan Hamilton; Jane Bledsoe, 1983 May; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Juan Hamilton, 1983 May 18; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Bill Martin; Charles Coles, 1983 June 15-1983 July 29; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Margaret Bailey Doogan; Albuquerque and Kramer; Hayden Herrera, 1983 August 10-1983 September 17; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Out-takes, "Sounds of Seeing" (Box 15)
      - Untitled, circa 1979-circa 1983; 1 sound tape reels (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Sandy Fox, 1980 December 11; 1 sound tape reels (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Kathy Huffman, Long Beach Museum of Art, 1981 January 8; 1 sound tape reels (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Hal Glickman, 1981 January 9; 1 sound tape reels (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Nancy Berman, Skirball Museum, 1981-02-05; 1 sound tape reels (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Tony Duquette, 1981 June 2; 1 sound tape reels (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - KUSC "Live from Trump's", 1984-1986 (Box 15)
    - Ruth Bowman with Unidentified Guests, 1984 October 20; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Ruth Bowman with Lloyd Hamrol, David Martin, and Al Nodal, 1985 May 4; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Ruth Bowman with Mary Hunt Halenberg, Edward Maeder, and Jerry Pudnay, 1985 October 5; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Myra Livingston with Unidentified Guests, 1986 August 23; 1 sound tape reels (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - American Abstract Artists, 1963-1965 (Box 15)
    alphabetized by interview subject's name
    - Bolotowsky, Ilya (transcript), 1963 November 5; 2 sound tape reels (Box 15, Folder 11-12)
    - Browne, Rosalind Bengelsdorf (transcript), circa 1963-circa 1965; 2 sound tape reels (Box 15, Folder 13-14)
    - Diller, Burgoyne (transcript), 1964 March 21; 3 sound tape reels; 1 sound cassette (Box 15, Folder 15-17)
    - Ferren, John (transcript), 1964 October 28; 2 sound tape reels (Box 15, Folder 18-20)
    - Holty, Carl, 1964 April 3; 6 sound tape reels (Box 15, Folder 21-23)
    - Holty, Carl (transcript), 1964 April 3 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Holty, Carl, 1967 January 2; 2 sound tape reels (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Holtzman, Harry (transcript), 1964 May 9; 3 sound tape reels (Box 20, Folder 3-5)
    - Lassaw, Ibram (transcript), 1964 May 9; 4 sound tape reels (Box 20, Folder 6-8)
    - Lipchitz, Jacques (transcript), 1965 April 7 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Lipchitz, Jacques (transcript), 1965 April 24; 4 sound tape reels (Box 21, Folder 2-4)
    - Mason, Alice (transcript), undated; 4 sound tape reels (Box 21, Folder 5-6)
    - McNeil, George (transcript), 1964 February 12; 2 sound tape reels (Box 21, Folder 7-8)
    - Morris, George L. K. (transcript), 1963 December 17; 2 sound tape reels (Box 25, Folder 1-2)
    - Reinhardt, Ad (transcript), 1964 May 10; 1 sound tape reels (Box 25, Folder 3-4)
  - WNYC "Views on Art" Radio Program, 1967-1973 (Box 16)
    - Amaya, Mario, 1972 September 1; 1969 January 9; 2 sound tape reels (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Andrews, Benny, 1973 May 1; 1 sound tape reels (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Ashton, Dore, 1972 June 15; 1 sound tape reels (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Atkinson, Tracy, 1968 January; 1 sound tape reels (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Barnet, Will, 1972 November 14; 1 sound tape reels (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Baro, Gene, 1969 January 9; 1 sound tape reels (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Baur, John I. H. and Ruth Bowman (transcript), 1969 April 30; 1969 April 24; 2 sound tape reels (Box 16, Folder 7-8)
    - Bothmer, Bernard, 1973 September 11; 1 sound tape reels (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Breeskin, Adelyn and Donald Karshan, 1967 October 6; 1 sound tape reels (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Brooks, James, 1973 May 15; 1 sound tape reels (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Brown, J. Carter, 1971 December 1; 1 sound tape reels (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Calas, Nicholas, 1971 December 9; 1 sound tape reels (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Cameron, Duncan, 1972 June 29; 1 sound tape reels (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Chryssa, 1973 April 10; 1 sound tape reels (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - D'Amico, Victor, 1969 November 6; 1 sound tape reels (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - D'Archangelo, Allan, 1973 March 20; 1 sound tape reels (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - D'Harnoncourt, Rene, 1967 October 23; 1 sound tape reels (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Esman, Rosa, 1971 June 14; 1 sound tape reels (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Flavin, Dan, 1970 February 12; 1 sound tape reel; 1 sound cassette (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Frankenstein, Alfred, 1970 September; 1 sound tape reels (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Freudenheim, Tom, 1969 September 3; 1 sound tape reels (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Fry, Edward, 1969; 2 sound tape reels (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Goncharova, Inna and Mikihail Bruk, 1972 September 19; 1 sound tape reels (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Grosser, Maurice, 1971 January 3; 1 sound tape reels (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Guggenheim, Peggy, 1969 January 23; 1 sound tape reel; 1 sound cassette (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Hamilton, George Heard, 1971 July 7; 1 sound tape reels (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Harithas, James, 1973 June 5; 1 sound tape reels (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Hess, Thomas B., 1969 March 13; 1 sound tape reels (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Hightower, John, 1969 October 2; 1 sound tape reel; 1 sound cassette (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Hopper, Edward, circa 1967-circa 1973; 1 sound tape reels (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Hopps, Walter, 1974 December 13; 1 sound tape reels (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Hornik, Lita and John Bernard Myers, 1972 May 18; 1972 May 25; 2 sound tape reels (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Hoving, Thomas and Henry Geldzahler, 1967 October 24; 1 sound tape reels (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Indiana, Robert and Carl Weinhardt, 1971 November; 1 sound tape reels (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Kahn, Wolf, 1971 March 11; 1973 March 17; 1 sound tape reels (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Kaplan, Mrs. J. M. and Roy Moyer, 1967 December 6; 1967 November 30; 1 sound tape reels (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Kaprow, Alan, 1968 March 7; 1 sound tape reels (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Katz, Alex, 1973 April 3; 1 sound tape reels (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - King, William, 1973 March 20; 1 sound tape reels (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Kozloff, Max, 1970 June 23; 1 sound tape reels (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Laning, Edward, 1972 March 13; 1 sound tape reels (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Lerner, Abram, 1968 September 5; 1 sound tape reels (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Marsciano, Nicholas, 1973 April 10; 1 sound tape reels (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - McCoy, Garnet, 1971 December 13; 1 sound tape reels (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - McKendry, John, 1968 April; 1 sound tape reels (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - McShine, Kynaston, 1968 March 29; 1 sound tape reels (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Messer, Thomas, 1967 October 24; 1 sound tape reels (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Miller, Samuel C., 1969 June 5; 1 sound tape reels (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Oberhuber, Konrad, 1971 December 13; 1 sound tape reels (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Ortiz, Rafael and Mrs. Marimar Quintana, 1970 November 23; 1 sound tape reels (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Parker, Harry, 1969 July 24; 1 sound tape reels (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Pepper, Beverly, 1970 November 23; 1 sound tape reels (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Ripley, Dillon S., 1969 September 9; 1 sound tape reels (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Rosenblum, Robert, 1970 May 28; 1 sound tape reels (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Rosenstein, Sir John, 1967 October 11; 1 sound tape reels (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Rubin, William, 1968 March; 1 sound tape reels (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Selz, Peter, 1969 October; 1 sound tape reels (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Slade, Roy, 1971 December 13; 1 sound tape reels (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Sleigh, Sylvia, 1973 January 30; 1 sound tape reels (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Smith, Leon Polk, 1970 November 9; 1 sound tape reels (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Sterne, Hedda, 1970 April 20; 1 sound tape reels (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Taylor, Betty Blayton, 1968 September 26; 1 sound tape reels (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Taylor, Dr. Joshua, 1971 December 13; 1 sound tape reels (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Taylor, Lisa, 1973 March 27; 1 sound tape reels (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Ultra Violet, 1968 July 1; 1 sound tape reels (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Wayne, June, 1968 May 21; 1 sound tape reels (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Wheeler, Monroe, 1968 September 12; 1 sound tape reels (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Wilke, Ulfert, 1971 May 12; 1 sound tape reels (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Wines, James, 1971 November 15; 1 sound tape reels (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Woolfenden, William, 1970 June 2; 1 sound tape reels (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Young, Mahonri Sharp, 1970 July 14; 1 sound tape reels (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Digitized Copies of WNYC "Views on Art" Radio Programs, 43 Sound discs (CD) (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Digitized Copies of WNYC "Views on Art" Radio Programs, 15 Sound discs (CD) (Box 24, Folder 1)